Eric Baze

2806 Gettysburg Drive, Austin, TX 78745-7530
469.644.4812 / eric@ericbaze.com / @ericbaze
ericbaze.com / dribbble.com/ericbaze / linkedin.com/in/ericbaze

Summary

I have 14 years of experience creating and managing all aspects of online experiences. I specialize in visual design, front-end development, content development and social media within a marketing context for desktop and mobile device delivery.

Secondary skills related to this include user experience, information architecture, back-end development, and server administration. I also have experience in print design, photography, and digital audio/video production.

Experience

UX/UI Designer

Digby, October 2012 - Present

Lead designer for all internal Digby branding and marketing initiatives as well as outside client services. This includes visual design, user experience, front-end development, and copyediting for desktop and mobile devices. Specific ongoing projects include identity design, brand positioning, and a complete redesign of all online [web, email] and offline [print, promotional, exhibit] materials.

Client Services work includes ongoing visual design, user experience, front-end development and maintenance of several client mobile sites using a variety of responsive design practices and frameworks. Some involvement with Digby's Localpoint product development in a similar capacity.

Visual Designer

Continuum Analytics, 5/2012 - 10/2012

On a consulting basis, functioned as principal designer to the company. Primary responsibilities included visual design and front-end development of all online properties and promotional materials, including content development. Secondary responsibilities included some pre-launch consulting on user experience for a SaaS product.

Senior Web Developer

Dallas County Community College District, 11/2005 - 5/2012

Team Lead responsible for managing all aspects of the college's digital media presence under the supervision of the Director of Marketing and Public Information. Hands-on experience with visual design, user experience, front-end production, content development, social media, email marketing, SEO, analytics, back-end development, and server administration.

Major projects include two complete redesigns of the college web site using vastly different technology stacks, initial launch and successful growth programs for social media and email marketing strategies, and introduction of mobile-optimized micro sites as marketing tools.

Creative Coordinator

InterCall, 5/2002 - 11/2005

Primary visual designer, developer and content editor responsible for managing all aspects of ConferenceCall.com and discount-branded web sites under the supervision of the Senior Director of Marketing Communications.

Major projects include development of custom content management systems and customer acquisition systems focusing on analytics and ROI in the years before such products were commonly available to small businesses.

Secondary responsibilities include visual design and production for digital advertising, email marketing, print collateral, and development of branding standards. Each project included significant copywriting and editing for both print and online materials.

Other Related Experience

Adjunct Faculty, DCCCD, 2007-2011 Adjunct Faculty, UT-Dallas, 2009 Training Specialist, South Texas College, 1998 Web Producer, Travelocity, 2001 Information Architect, Move, 2000 Affiliate Network Support, Match.com, 1999-2000

Education

Master of Fine Arts

Art & Technology, 2007 The University of Texas at Dallas

Bachelor of Applied Arts & Sciences

Applied Business Technology, 1998
The University of Texas at Brownsville

Master of Arts

Art & Technology, 2006
The University of Texas at Dallas

Associate of Applied Science

Information Management Technology, 1993 Texas State Technical College - Harlingen

Skills

Adobe Creative Suite
Omnigraffle
Twitter Bootstrap
Responsive Design
UNIX, Mac, Windows
WCAG, TAC 206 and 508c
Print collateral design
Social media development
Content development

LAMP & WIMP technology stacks
HTML5 & CSS3
Blueprint CSS
Mobile-optimized design
Android and iOS
UX standards & practices
Basic digital audio/video editing
Email Marketing

Coda
Javascript / jQuery
960.gs
Cross-browser compatibility
PHP/MySQL
Basic UX research
Digital photography & retouching

Copywriting & editing